Peter L. Goss Collection on Margaret Bourke-White
Peter L. Goss Collection on Margaret Bourke-White
1966
Goss, Peter L.
0.25 linear ft.
Correspondence, photographs, printed material, most relating to an exhibit of the work of photographer Margaret Bourke-White at Syracuse University in the spring of 1966.
3367117
Biographical History
Margaret Bourke-White (1904-1971) was an American photographer, war correspondent and author. Among her notable achievements, she was the first foreign photographer permitted to take pictures of Soviet Industry, the first female war correspondent, and the first female photographer for Life magazine. Her papers are deposited at Syracuse University Library's Special Collections Research Center.
Peter L. Goss is a graduate of Syracuse University, a professor emeritus of architectural history at the University of Utah and a documentary photographer. In 1966 Goss was a graduate student and chairman of VISAGE, a student photography group responsible for organizing and mounting the exhibit to which this collection relates.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Peter L. Goss Collection on Margaret Bourke-White consists of correspondence, photographs, printed material and published material, the bulk of which relate to an exhibit of Bourke-White's work in 1966 at Syracuse University.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical.
Related Material
See also the
Margaret Bourke-White Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Photography; Bourke-White, Margaret, 1904-1971.; Goss, Peter L.; S.I. Newhouse School of Public Communications; Portrait of myself.; Photojournalists -- United States -- 20th century.; Photographers -- United States -- 20th century.; Women photographers.; Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Photographers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Peter L. Goss, 2011.
Inventory
- Donor documentation
  - Inventory, detailed description of collection contents, provided by donor (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous, 1966; letters from Goss, one from Bourke-White's secretary, and a press release (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Related to exhibit, 1966; photos of Bourke-White, Goss, students, faculty (Box 1)
  - Unrelated to exhibit, 1966; fashion photos taken by Goss for class assignments (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Clippings, 1966; two items relating to exhibit (Box 1)
  - Exhibit catalogs, 1966; also includes brochure about the Newhouse School's photography program (Box 1)
- Published material, by Bourke-White
  - Article, "The 30s," Hyphen, vol. 1, May 1966 (Box 1)
  - Book, Portrait of Myself, signed and inscribed to Goss (Box 1)